Ali Zare Software engineer | Frontend Developer | Blockchain Researcher

≛ Male 💡 Tehran, Iran 🛗 21 Sep 1991 📞 +989101011426 💌 aliiizaareee@gmail.com 床 https://www.aliiz.ir

Profile

I am a front-end developer with over 5 years of experience in this field. My expertise lies in JavaScript and TypeScript, and I have been able to utilize these languages in various projects. Additionally, I have strong experience in working with React and Next.js frameworks and have been able to create visually appealing and efficient user interfaces using these tools. Throughout my career, I have worked as a frontend development team lead in multiple projects, successfully coordinating cross-functional development teams and acting as a team leader.

I possess excellent communication and collaboration skills with designers, backend developers, and project managers, and always prioritize the quality and performance of the applications while adhering to coding standards. Furthermore, I am constantly learning and improving my skills to deliver the best performance in future teams and projects.

Professional Experience

Frontend Developer, Charisma Financial Group

I am currently working at Charisma Financial Group and working on the Charisma website and gift card project using React and Next.js. In these projects, I utilize React and Next.js frameworks to develop and optimize websites.

Nov 2023 – present Tehran, Iran

Apr 2020 - Nov 2023

Tehran, Iran

Frontend Developer, Tehran Stock Exchange

I was the first person to introduce and utilize React JS and Next JS technologies in this company.

By utilizing React JS and Next JS, I was able to enhance and improve the performance of web application projects.

As a leader of the front-end development team, I facilitated the improvement of development processes and collaboration within the team.

Provided necessary training and guidance to the team on using React JS and Next JS, as well as implementing best practices and design patterns in software development.

Frontend (Mobile) Developer, Banimode

During my work experience at Banimode, I developed the Banimode mobile app using React Native. I analyzed app crashes using Sentry, resolved bugs on different devices, and improved the user experience by monitoring user behaviors with Firebase. I provided solutions to the UX team to enhance the app's usability.

Jan 2020 – Apr 2020 Tehran, Iran

Frontend (Mobile) Developer, First Eurasia E-Commerce

In my previous role at CompanyFirst Eurasia E-commerce, I served as the Front-end Team Leader and successfully completed projects such as FinTech and CRM using React Native. These projects were deployed on various platforms including mobile, web, desktop, and PWA. In addition, I mentored three interns during this period, providing guidance, training, and support to enhance their performance and professional development.

Jul 2018 – Jan 2020 Tehran, Iran

Education

Master of Software Engineering, Islamic Azad University Science and Research Branch

2014 – 2016 Amol, Iran

Bachelor(BSc/BA) of Software Engineering, Amol Institute of Higher Education

2012 – 2014 Amol, Iran

Associate of Software Engineering, Technical Institute Of Behshahr - Imam Khomeini

2009 – 2012 Behshahr, Iran

Skills

Development

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React is
- React Native
- Next js

State Management

- Redux(thunk
- toolkit)
- Context Api
- MobX
- Recoil

Design systems

- CSS
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- Styled component
- MŬI
- Antd

Tools

- Git- Git Flow -monorepo
- Firebase
- CodePush
- Sentry
- StoryBook
- Webpack
- Vite.js
- Docker
- Scrum methodology
- Unit Test (jest)
- Integration Test(jest)
- End to End Test(puppeteer)

aliiizaareee@gmail.com 1/1